{

  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Q1. When equilibrium is reached inside the two half-cells of the electrochemical cells, what is the net voltage across the electrodes?",
      "answers": {
        "a": ">1",
        "b": "<1",
        "c": "= 0",
        "d": "Not defined"
      },
	  "correctAnswer": "c",
      
    },
	{
      "question": "Q2. Which of the following is not a generally used electrolyte in the salt bridges used to connect the two half-cells of an electrochemical cell?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "NaCl",
        "b": "KNO<sub>3</sub>",
        "c": "KCl",
        "d": "ZnSO<sub>4</sub>"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",

    },
    {
      "question": "Q3. Which of the following factors does not affect the electrode potential of an electrode?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Nature of the electrode (metal)",
        "b": "Temperature of the solution",
        "c": "Molarity of the solution",
        "d": "Size of the electrode"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",

    },
	{
      "question": "Q4.Why are the saturated solutions of electrolytes for the salt bridge prepared in agar-agar jelly or gelatin?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "The jelly acts as an electrolyte",
        "b": "It helps the electrolytes to mix with the contents of the half cells",
        "c": "It helps maintain the electrical polarity between the two half-cell solutions",
        "d": " It keeps the electrolyte in semi-solid phase and prevents it from mixing with the two half-cell solutions"
      },

      "correctAnswer": "d",

    },
	{
      "question": "Q5.Which of the following conditions are satisfied when the cell reaction in the electrochemical cell is spontaneous?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "ΔG° > 0",
        "b": "E° < 0",
        "c": "E° = 0",
        "d": "ΔG° < 0"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "d",

    },
	
	{
      "question": "Q6.When the salt bridge is removed from a cell, its voltage?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "will increase",
        "b": "will decrease to half",
        "c": "will decrease to zero",
        "d": "will not change"
      },
     
      "correctAnswer": "c",

    },
	{
      "question": "Q7.The cell constant of a conductivity cell?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Changes with a change of concentration of electrolyte",
        "b": "Remains constant for a cell",
        "c": "Changes with a change of electrolyte",
        "d": "Changes with change in temperature"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",

    },
	{
      "question": "Q8.Anodizing creates an oxide layer on the surface of a metal that is:",
      "answers": {
        "a": "thicker than the naturally occurring oxide",
        "b": "thinner than the naturally occurring oxide",
        "c": "much lighter than the naturally occurring oxide",
        "d": "a more porous surface than the naturally occurring oxide"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",

    },
	{
      "question": "Q9.What is the product formed at the cathode in the electrolysis of aqueous CuSO<sub>4</sub>?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Copper metal",
        "b": "Oxygen gas",
        "c": "Hydrogen gas",
        "d": "Sulphur"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "a",

    },
	{
      "question": "Q10.Electrolytic cell contains?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Electrolytes must have same concentration",
        "b": "Electrolytes contains different concentration",
        "c": "Electrode should be of varied pressure",
        "d": "Reference electrode is used"
      },
      
      "correctAnswer": "b",

    }
  ]

}
